Johnny Otis Collection, 1949-2012 SC 106
Archives of African American Music and Culture
- 4. Radio Airchecks, Johnny Otis Show
  - 4.2. KPFK (Los Angeles) and KPFA (Berkeley), 1982-1994
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 23, 1983-02-26; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Margie Evans, Don Julian, Janice Lafon, Al Williams, Dewey Terry, Bernice Turner, Connie Morgan, Buddy King
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Don & Dewey, Joe Liggins, Rayovacs, Chris Kenner, Five Royales, Johnny Otis Show featuring Charles Williams, Coasters, Drifters, Richard Berry, Fats Domino, Hank Ballard & The Midnighters, and Lloyd Price. Otis and guests introduce records. Live comedy segment. Otis promotes his food drive for the homeless, talks to guests about the blues and The South, and then talks on the telephone with Buddy King.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 27; '50s Memories, 1983-03-07; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Billy Foster
      EC10 2569; EC10 2570
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/890r76mm7v
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Buster Brown, Chords, Martha & The Vandellas, Jessie Hill, Skyliners, Coasters, Moonglows, Champs, Fats Domino, Bobby Day, Cadets, Cleftones, Bobbettes, Sam Cooke, Jive Bombers, Clovers, and El Dorados. Otis talks about Bobby Day.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Mel Walker, Mel Williams, Al Rapone, Big Joe Turner, Medallions, Ray Charles, Maurice Williams & The Zodiacs, Etta James, Edna McGriff, Turbans, and Jesse Belvin. Otis talks about Queen Ida. Otis and singer songwriter Billy Foster (The Medallions) talk about how Foster got started in music, his sons, his current songwriting projects, and then they take phone calls. Otis discusses how "Roll With Me Henry" came about.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 28; Where Were You in '62? - Music of the 1960s, 1983-03-21; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2571; EC10 2572
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/257980188p
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Junior Walker & The All-Stars, Sam & Dave, Bar-Kays, Joe Tex, Supremes, Marvelettes, Smokey Robinson & The Miracles, Barbara Lewis, Wilson Pickett, Aretha Franklin, Billy Stuart, Etta James, and Jerry Butler. Otis takes phone calls and audience members reminisce about the '60s.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Mary Wells, Martha & The Vandellas, Marvin Gaye & Tammi Terrell, Aaron Neville, Stevie Wonder, James Brown, Ray Charles, Arthur Conley, Barrett Strong, Four Tops, Cannonball Adderley, Sam & Dave, Rufus Thomas, and Ben E. King. Otis takes phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 29; Dedication Night, 1983-03-28; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2573; EC10 2574
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q27z60k77p
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Chuck Berry, Little Willie John, Sonny Knight, Drifters, Martha Reeves, Ray Charles, Richard Berry, Etta James, Johnny Ace, Hank Ballard & The Midnighters, Penguins, and Smokey Robinson & The Miracles.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Platters, Clyde McPhatter & The Drifters, Aretha Franklin, Skyliners, Lloyd Price, Heartbeats, B.B. King, Bobby Day, Moonglows, Fleetwoods, Jessie Hill, Coasters, Silhouettes, and Little Richard. Otis promotes his food drive for the homeless and asks for volunteers.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 32; Muddy Waters Memorial, 1983-05-02; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ernie Andrews, Bob Epstein
      EC10 2575; EC10 2576
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q67j72vq80
      Otis plays the music of Muddy Waters, Ernie K-Doe, Otis Redding, Robins, Roy Milton, and Ernie Andrews. Otis and guests talk about several friends in R&B who have recently passed away or are ill. Otis and singer Ernie Andrews talk about their early days, Andrews' early career and first records, the song "Parker's Mood" and jazz vocalist King Pleasure." Otis and guests take phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 33, 1983-05-09; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ken Jones, Robert Farrell
      EC10 2577; EC10 2578
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/5547725x33
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Billy Stewart, Ike & Tina Turner, Moonglows, Little Richard, Bobby Lewis, Carla Thomas, Barrett Strong, Delores Gibson, Albert King, Rufus Thomas, Dorothy Love Coates & The Gospel Harmonettes, Joe Tex, and Louis Jordan & The Tympany Five. Otis announces mystery record contest for the night, talks about a local man who is in prison, and takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Professor Longhair, James Brown, Delmar "Mighty Mouth" Evans, Frankie Ford, Supremes, Bunny Siegler, Meditation Singers, LaVern Baker, Betty Swan, Ruth Brown, Jimmy Reed, Rivingtons, and Aretha Franklin. Otis announces upcoming concert and talks to Malcolm Klugman about the Heritage Festival in New Orleans. Otis talks about the internationality and inter-regionalism of the blues, takes phone calls, talks about a new gospel movie and greets Ken Jones. Otis and Los Angeles City Council member Robert Farrell (on phone) talk about the loss of the R&B club scene and lack of young R&B musicians in Los Angeles.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 35; Jimmy Reed Special, 1983-05-23; 1986-07-28 [possible rebroadcast date listed]; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Blind Joe Hill, Bernie Pearl, Richard Berry
      EC10 2579; EC10 2580; EC10 2362
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/p38w32xj4d
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Ray Charles, Fiestas, Bobby Marchand, Jimmy Reed, Ruth Brown, Bull Moose Jackson, Ray Sharpe, Swan Silvertones, Lee Dorsey, Richard Berry, Silhouettes, and Smiley Lewis. Richard Berry talks about his return to college. Otis takes phone calls and announces upcoming shows.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Richard Berry, Jimmy Reed, Johnny Otis and Sugarcane Harris, Stevie Wonder, Five Satins, Dominoes, and Moms Mabley. Otis talks with Richard Berry. Live performance of "You Got Me Busy" by Hill and Pearl, joined by Otis for "Run Joe" and unidentified song.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Little Willie John, Martha & the Vandellas and Ivory Joe Hunter. Live performances by Bernie Pearl and Blind Joe Hill. Live performance by Otis, Pearl, Hill, and Berry. Otis and guests talk about the blues, Hill's hometown, Louis Jordan, and Pearl's hometown and influences. Comedy segment.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 38, 1983-06-13; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Hannah Dean, Charles Williams
      EC10 2581; EC10 2582
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/267683363b
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of The Midnighters, Olympics, Brook Benton & Dinah Washington, Little Willie Littlefield, Bo Diddley, Moms Mabley, Jimmy Reed, Preston Love & Shuggie Otis, Jesse Belvin, Count Basie, and Elmore James. Otis and singer Hannah Dean talk about some of her past performances. Live performance of "Jesus" by Dean with Otis and Williams.
      Tape 2: Live performance of "Because He Lives" by Dean and Williams. Otis and Dean talk about her new restaurant and Otis introduces her record, ""Open Sesame." Otis plays the music Preston Love, Frankie Lymon & The Teenagers, Earl Bostic, Aretha Franklin, Saunders King, Jackie Wilson, Fats Domino, Drifters, and Tommy Tucker. Otis talks about Beto Lovato's upcoming concerts and guitarist Saunders King.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 39, 1983-06-20; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2583; EC10 2584
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/g54x51pr3v
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Little Richard, Hank Ballard & The Midnighters, Chuck Willis, Jimmy Witherspoon, Cleftones, Inez Fox, Etta James, Gene Chandler, James Brown, Ray Charles, Big Maybelle, Five Satins, Dee Clark, Ritchie Valens, Hank Ballard, Cadets, Harmonizing Four, Little Willie John, Moonglows, and Sam Cooke. Comedy segment, then Otis takes phone calls. Otis and friends compare Big Maybelle's and Jerry Lee Lewis's recordings of "Whole Lotta Shakin' Goin' On."
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Sticks McGhee, Ray Charles, Skyliners, Jackie Wilson, Big Joe Turner, Kingsmen, Clovers, LaVern Baker, Ruth Brown, Robins, Gene & Eunice, Jimmy Jones, Coasters, and James Brown. Comedy segment, then Otis takes phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 40; 4th of July Special, 1983-07-04; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2585; EC10 2586; EC10 3669
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q87b790s3q
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Joe Houston, Ikettes, Lowell Fulson, Pee Wee Crayton, Young Jessie, LaVern Baker, Mighty Clouds of Joy, Clifford Curry, Curtis Mayfield & The Impressions, Roy Brown, Bobby Bland, Count Basie, and Brook Benton. Comedy segment, then Otis takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Barbara George, Ernie K-Doe, Wilson Pickett, Bo Diddley, Mary Johnson, Etta James, Oscar McLolly, Charles Brown, Mighty Clouds of Joy, Sam & Dave, Tampa Red, Ivory Joe Hunter, Fats Domino, Marvelettes, and Little Esther Phillips. Comedy segment, then Otis takes phone calls.
      Tape 3 (EC 10" 3669): Otis plays the music of Joe Houston, The Ikettes, Lowell Fulson, Pee Wee Crayton, Young Jessie, LaVern Baker, Mighty Clouds of Joy, Clifford Curry, Impressions, Roy Brown, Bobby Bland, Count Basie, and Brook Benton.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 41, 1983-07-11; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2587; EC10 2588
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/762336p43w
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Big Joe Turner, Larry Williams, Louis Jordan, Del Vikings, Bobby Bland, Jacks, Charles Brown, Professor Alex Bradford, Ivory Joe Hunter, Stevie Wonder, Smokey Robinson & The Miracles, Martha & The Vandellas, and Supremes. Comedy segment, then Otis takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Sam & Dave, Otis Redding, Aretha Franklin, Clara Ward Singers, Erroll Garner, Little Richard, Willie Bobo, Muddy Waters, Moonglows, Junior Wells, Frankie Lymon & The Teenagers, Ron Holden, Frankie Ford, and Lee Andrews & The Harps. Otis takes phone calls followed by comedy segment, then Otis and Rob Heller talk about East Coast doo-wop.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 42, 1983-07-18; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ray Campi, Dootsie Williams
      EC10 2589
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/v93504zb2f
      Otis plays the music of Jackie Wilson, Louis Jordan & The Tympany Five, Lionel Hampton & Dinah Washington, Mongo Santamaria, John Lee Hooker, Vernon Green & The Medallions, Otis Redding, Five Keys, Doves, Ray Campi, Professor Alex Bradford, B.B. King, Big Jay McNeely, Little Willie John, Memphis Slim, and The Penguins. Ray Campi, aka "King of Rockabilly," talks with Otis about European audiences and Campi's latest album.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 43; Johnny Otis Retrospective, 1983-07-25; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2590; EC10 2591
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/b39722ps1p
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Margie Evans, Big Joe Turner, Cavaliers, Johnny Otis, Big Mama Thornton, Bill Doggett, Eddie "Cleanhead" Vinson, Robins, Tony Allen, Fiestas, Gladys Knight & The Pips, Louis Jordan with Johnny & Shuggie Otis, Charles Brown, Guitar Slim Green, Roosevelt Sykes, and Gene & Eunice. Comedy segment.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 44, 1983-08-01; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Paul Robi, Bill Griffith
      EC10 2592; EC10 2593
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/b29b19m44h
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of The Olympics, Barrett Strong, Bobby "Blue" Bland, Marvelettes, Clyde McPhatter, Slim & Slam, Slim Gaylord, Willie Mabon, Rays, Platters, and Rufus Thomas. Otis and Paul Robi (an original member of the Platters) talk about Slim & Slam, the Platters early days, how they got signed to Mercury with The Penguins, and the Platters' current lineup. Otis and guests take phone calls and talk about current American musical culture.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Drifters, Platters, Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Hound Dog Taylor, Inez Fox, Louis Jordan, Jimmy Hughes, Muddy Waters, and "Pine Top" Smith. Otis and Robi talk about his song, "Only You," and his early years and influences. Otis and Bill Griffith talk about the old days together. Otis and guests take phone calls. Griffith talks about what he's currently doing with his Roller Derby and about old video tapes of The Johnny Otis Show television series.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 45, 1983-08-08; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Plas Johnson
      EC10 2594; EC10 2595
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/514n59wd3h
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Shorty Long, Coasters, Fats Domino, Otis Redding, Chuck Berry, Sixteens, Plas Johnson, Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Richard Berry, Staple Singers, Slim Harpo, and Frankie Lymon. Otis talks to Mrs. Joe Turner (Pat Turner) on the phone about Roy Milton's medical condition and planned benefit, also talks to Big Joe Turner and invites him to the next show. Otis talks to tenor saxophonist Plas Johnson about his new song "Grease Patrol," his new album, and Screamin' Jay Hawkins' "Constipation Blues." Otis promotes upcoming festivals and takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Junior Walker & The All-Stars, Johnny Hodges, Dirty Red, Billie Holiday, Olympics, Jimmy Reed, Barbara Mason, Jay McShann, Ruth Brown, Joe Tex, and Ray Charles. Comedy segment. Otis and guests take phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 46, 1983-08-15; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Al DeMarino, Clara Ward Singers, Charles Williams
      EC10 2596; EC10 2597
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/930b88wq5j
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Red Prysock, Inez Fox, Doves, Supremes, Billie Holiday, Otis Redding, and Stevie Ray Vaughan. Otis and Al Demarino talk about Frankie Lymon, Otis Redding, and Stevie Ray Vaughan. Live performance of "Michael Row the Boat Ashore" by the Clara Ward Singers. Otis and the Ward Singers talk about how they got together and give their opinions on pop stars recording gospel albums.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Swan Silvertones, Clara Ward Singers, Frankie Lymon, Johnny Otis Show, Del Vikings, Brook Benton and Dinah Washington. Otis and the Clara Ward Singers discuss the Swan Silvertones, then give a live performance of "When We All Get to Heaven," "The Old Campground," "In the Prayer Room," and join Charles Williams on "Oh Happy Day."
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 47, 1983-08-29; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Addie Lee Bobo, Beto Lovato, Charles Williams
      EC10 2598
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/k61r46xm7q
      Otis plays the music of Big Joe Turner, Muddy Waters, Frankie Lymon & The Teenagers, Billie Holiday, El Dorados, Nappy Brown, Otis Redding, Jay McShann, Lightnin' Hopkins, Johnny Otis Show featuring Addie Lee Bobo and Charles Williams, Louis Jordan, Bobby Bland, and Eddie Vinson. Otis talks to Beto Lovato, Addie Lee Bobo, and Charles Williams about their careers, influences, and hometowns.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 48; Labor Day Special, 1983-09-05; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2599; EC10 2600
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/188158ht7g
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of The Silhouettes, Chuck Berry, Fats Waller, Duke Ellington, Louis Jordan, Aretha Franklin, Bo Diddley, Johnny Otis Show, Harmonizing Four, Earl Bostic, Clyde McPhatter, Billie Holiday, Jimmie Lunceford, Richard Berry, Sam Cooke, and Lee Dorsey. Otis and friends discuss the song "Louie, Louie" and the obscenity debate surrounding it. Comedy segment followed by Otis taking phone calls. Otis and friends talk about a local station's "Louie Louie" marathon.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Plas Johnson, Bobby Bland, Fats Domino, Johnny Otis Show featuring Addie Lee Bobo, Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Paul Robeson, Roy Milton, Brook Benton, Sam Cooke, Joe Houston, Little Walter, Mexi Marlow, Count Basie, Johnny Otis Show featuring Shuggie Otis, Coasters, Percy Mayfield, Detroit Junior, and Little Willie Littlefield. Otis takes phone calls followed by a comedy segment.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 49, 1983-09-12; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Al Frazier, John Outterbridge, Bernie Pearl
      EC10 2601; EC10 2602
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/534f661h35
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Louis Jordan, Thurston Harris, Big Maybelle, Blind Lemon Jefferson, Bull Moose Jackson, Elmore James, Sister Rosette Tharpe & Marie Knight, Jimmy McCracklin, Bobby Bland, Clifton Chenier, and Koko Taylor. Otis talks with artist and activist John Outterbridge.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Little Willie John, Billie Holiday, Louis Jordan, Little Richard, Dominoes, Muddy Waters, Albert King, Rivingtons, Ted Taylor, Little Miss Cornshucks, Tiny Bradshaw, Erroll Garner, Julia Lee, Johnny Otis, Cleftones, Johnny "Guitar" Watson, Wilson Pickett, LaVern Baker, and Jimmie Lunceford. Otis and guests talk about upcoming blues festival and Ella Johnson. Otis and Al Frazier (The Rivingtons) talk with a friend on the phone and give a live performance of "Roll On." Frazier talks about performing "The Bells" and how The Rivingtons chose their name. Otis and guests talk about Little Miss Cornshucks, then talk to Rocky Turner Wilson, Jr. of The Rivingtons (on the phone). Otis also has phone conversations with Mike Akopov and Ed Thomas, who discusses Necktie Nate.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 53; Trivia Night, 1983-10-24; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.
      EC10 2603
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/534f661h4g
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Professor Longhair, Lloyd Price, Temptations, Annie Laurie, Ritchie Valens, Johnny Otis Show, Otis Redding, Faye Adams, Harmonizing Four, Del Vikings, Preston Love & Shuggie Otis, T-Bone Walker, Lowell Fulson, Harptones, and Santo & Johnny. Otis poses a trivia question for the listeners, takes phone calls, and promotes an upcoming gig, followed by a comedy segment.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 54; Halloween Special, 1983-10-31; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): John Patton
      EC10 2604; EC10 2605
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/b49425rn2n
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Sam & Dave, Ray Dobard, Dee Clark, Dells, Falcons, Lowell Fulson, Lionel Hampton, Count Basie, Aretha Franklin, Ernie Freeman, Staple Singers, Nina Simone, Everly Brothers, Marvin Gaye & Kim Weston, Gene & Eunice, Marie Adams and more. Otis talks with John Patton about Black composers and promotion of Black artists and music history in their radio shows, then takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Fats Domino, Amos Milburn, Tiny Bradshaw, Ivory Joe Hunter, Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Larry Darnell, Eugene Church, Shields, Shirley & Lee, Lightnin' Hopkins, Slim Gaylord, and Bo Diddley. Otis takes phone calls and asks a trivia question.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 55, 1983-11-07; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Addie Lee Bobo, Kirk Silsbee
      EC10 2606; EC10 2607
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/089227t02z
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of The El Dorados, Fats Domino, Barbara George, Olympics, Shep & The Limelights, Huey "Piano" Smith, Bull Moose Jackson, Johnny Otis Show, Jesse Belvin, Billy Eckstine Orchestra, Elmore James, Otis Redding, and Temptations. Comedy segment followed by discussion with journalist Kirk Silsbee about "Jubilee" broadcasts and recordings. Otis and Mal Klugman talk about a local benefit concert held by Big Joe Turner, then Otis takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Midnighters, Lonnie Johnson, Lee Dorsey, Ritchie Valens, Little Richard, Johnny Otis Show featuring Charles Williams and Shuggie Otis, Diablos, Peppermint Harris, Amos Milburn, Staple Singers, Supremes, Temptations, Johnny Otis Show featuring Addie Lee Bobo, Julie Stevens, and Ray Charles. Otis takes phone calls and asks a trivia question.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 56, 1983-11-14; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Son Seals, Julie Stevens, Truman Jacques, Tamara Hayes
      EC10 2608
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/f65v242201
      Otis plays the music of Pure Gold, Bobby Day, Carla Thomas, Son Seals, Harmonizing Four, Wilson Pickett, Julie Stevens, Junior Walker, Professor Longhair, Billie Holiday, Johnny Otis, and Shuggie Otis. Otis and Son Seals talk about his early influences, childhood, and current state of the blues. Otis and guests talk about what Julie Stevens is currently doing, the lean days in Otis's early career, and the lineup on Stevens' record "Blue Mood." Otis talks about Plas Johnson and the song "Hit That Jive, Jack."
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 57, 1983-11-28; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Melba Joyce, Ruben Guevara
      EC10 2609; EC10 2610
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/c08h44696k
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Fats Domino, Lee Dorsey, Etta James, Tony Allen, Wilson Pickett, Marie Adams, Melba Joyce, B.B. King, Little Junior Parker, Little Julian, and Ritchie Valens. Otis and Ruben Guevara (Ruben and the Jets) talk about Latino R&B in Los Angeles.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Bo Diddley, Jimmy Witherspoon, Wilbert Harrison, Spaniels, Chantels, Royal Gents, Wynonie Harris, Ivory Joe Hunter, Thurston Harris, Joe Simon, Chuck Berry, Billie Holiday, Hank Williams Sr., and Aretha Franklin. Otis and Guevara talk about the Latin music scene in Los Angeles. Otis has a trivia contest and talks about his new cable TV show. Otis and jazz singer Melba Joyce discuss her early influences. Otis and guests talk about fundamentalists who believe that R&B is the devil's music. Guevara talks about his musical influences, his new label and some new Latino/R&B groups in Los Angeles. Otis talks about Wynonie Harris.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 58, 1983-12-05; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ralph Williams
      EC10 2611; EC10 2612
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/8418618017
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Eddie Floyd, Turbans, Big Joe Turner, Coasters, Harptones, Lee Dorsey, Ray Charles, Count Basie, Clarence "Gatemouth" Brown, Huey "Piano" Smith, Earl Hines, and Lloyd Price. Otis has a trivia contest followed by comedy segment. Otis talks about a reunion in Europe of the classic lineup of Count Basie's band and then takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of James Brown, Roy Hamilton, Ray Brooks, Ike & Tina Turner, Hank Ballard, Marvin Gaye, Cleve Duncan & The Penguins, Cab Calloway, Amos Milburn, Supremes, Otis Redding, Jerry Butler, Jerry Lee Lewis, and Charles Brown. Otis introduces records with Ralph Williams, takes phone calls, promotes an upcoming gig, announces his talent search for a young female singer, and talks to Happy Harry.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, program 60; Shuggie Otis Retrospective, 1983-12-19; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Thee Royals Gents, Ruben Guevara, Johnny "Two-Voice" Morrisette, Shuggie Otis, Brenton Wood, Rob Heller
      EC10 2613; EC10 2614
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/g45148mr2s